<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Acupuncture</name>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="monk-acupuncture.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Xelial-1064/Homebrew/main/monk-acupuncture.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Way of Acupuncture" type="Archetype" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_WAY_OF_ACUPUNCTURE">
        <supports>Monastic Tradition</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Monks of the Way of Acupuncture study extensively in anatomy, allowing them to alter the ki flow in enemies and allies alike with surgical precision.</p>
            <p class="indent">Followers of the Way of Acupuncture opt for disabling their enemies and aiding their allies, for it is not in them to kill unless neccessary.</p>
            <div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ACUPUNCTURE_HEALING_FIST" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ACUPUNCTURE_ACUPUNCTURE" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ACUPUNCTURE_PAIN_REMOVAL" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ACUPUNCTURE_PARALYZING_BLOW" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Channels ki through pressure points.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ACUPUNCTURE_HEALING_FIST" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ACUPUNCTURE_ACUPUNCTURE" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ACUPUNCTURE_PAIN_REMOVAL" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ACUPUNCTURE_PARALYZING_BLOW" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
	<element name="Healing Fist" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ACUPUNCTURE_HEALING_FIST">
		<description>
			<p>At 3rd level, you gain the ability to activate certain pressure points in the body that accelerate natural healing processes. By spending 1 ki point, you can convert your punches into healing punches, allowing for any unarmed strikes made during your turn to be converted into healing fists. After 11th level you can use your flurry of blows following healing fists to heal with this feature without spending additional ki points. This feature also upgrades your flurry of blows, allowing you to heal 3 times at 14th level, upgrading again at 17th with 4 heals.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Special" usage="Ki">
			<description>By spending 2 ki point, you can convert your punches into healing punches, allowing for any unarmed strikes made during your turn to be converted into healing fists. After 11th level you can use your flurry of blows following healing fists to heal with this feature without spending additional ki points. This feature also upgrades your flurry of blows, allowing you to heal 3 times at 14th level, upgrading again at 17th with 4 heals.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
    <element name="Acupuncture" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ACUPUNCTURE_ACUPUNCTURE">
        <description>
            <p>At 6th level, you gain the ability to enhance your healing fists so that they heal for maximum value, but you suffer one level of exhaustion afterwards. Additionally, you learn how to treat the long-term effects of exhaustion. During a short rest you can perform acupuncture on others or yourself to remove 1 level of exhaustion and can even remove 5th level exhaustion. Long rests now heal 2 levels of exhaustion.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Exhaustion">
            <description>You gain the ability to enhance your healing fists so that they heal for maximum value, but you suffer one level of exhaustion afterwards. Additionally, you learn how to treat the long-term effects of exhaustion. During a short rest you can perform acupuncture on others or yourself to remove 1 level of exhaustion and can even remove 5th level exhaustion. Long rests now heal 2 levels of exhaustion.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Pain Removal" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ACUPUNCTURE_PAIN_REMOVAL">
        <description>
            <p>At 11th level, you gain the ability to activate certain pressure points in the brain that remove the ability to feel pain. By spending 1 ki, the target gains + 2 to AC, as their body is able to nimbly avoid attacks with flexibility unknown to others, and they gain resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage. Additionally, their movement speed is doubled, and do not suffer the effects of exhaustion while it is activated. This effect lasts for 1 hour, and they suffer a level of exhaustion at the end of this effect.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action" usage="Ki/Exhaustion">
            <description>Expend 1 ki to gain +2 AC, and resistance to bludgeoning piercing and slahing damage for 1 hour. Target suffers one level of exhaustion afterwards.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Paralyzing Blow" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ACUPUNCTURE_PARALYZING_BLOW">
        <description>
            <p>At 17th level, your knowledge of human anatomy and the flow of ki allows you to further enhance your stunning strike. When you hit another creature with a melee weapon attack, you can spend 2 ki points to attempt a paralyzing blow. The target must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or be paralyzed until the end of your next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Ki">
            <description>When you hit another creature with a melee weapon attack, you can spend 2 ki points to attempt a paralyzing blow. The target must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or be paralyzed until the end of your next turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
</elements>
